ABOUT ME

Hi, I am a UI Engineer & Designer. I have worked on a large-scale ReactJS web application, WordPress Migration, Angular/Bootstrap applications, mobile app design. I have experience building web/mobile apps and a published app in Apple and Google Play stores. I also have a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science and a diverse technical background. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and JavaScript frameworks while continuing to learn new technologies.

I love hackathons and creative collaboration!

SKILLS

UI DEVELOPMENT UI DESIGN UI PROTOTYPING

TECH TOOLS

Essentials:

HTML, Javascript (ES5/ES6+), CSS, SQL Frameworks: ReactJS, AngularJS(1+) Packages: npm, yarn, homebrew Static Site Generators: GatsbyJS CSS: SASS/SCSS, styled-components

Other Tooling:

Typescript, Storybook, Grunt, Express,

Firebase, GraphQL, REST/

APIs, OAuth, jQuery, Bootstrap, CircleCI, MongoDB, Jest, Abstract, Sketch, PUG, HAML, Flexbox, CSS Grid, Babel, Invision, Google AMP, Webpack, Google Web Designer, Agile, JIRA, Confluence, LernaJS, Lottie/SVG Animation, NodeJS

CMS:

Headless, Wordpress, Sitecore

Version Control:

Git/Github, Bitbucket

ADOBE CREATIVE CLOUD

Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, XD

EDUCATION

Bachelor Computer Science

Columbus State University

Web Developer Certification

Emory Continuing Education

LISA COPELAND

UI ENGINEER & DESIGNER

PORTFOLIO: http://www.stopdaydreaming.com

EMAIL: hello@stopdaydreaming.com

PHONE: 678.235.4961

GITHUB: https://github.com/stopdaydreaming

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Contractor

JUN2019 - CURRENT

Freelance UI Engineer

- Develop ReactJS components based on user stories
- Build ReactJS components for Arc Publishing ecosystem
- Strong knowledge of JavaScript (ES5, ES6+)
- Build components styling using SASS/SCSS
- Collaborative environment with paired programming

CLIENTS:

AJC.com: React Migration

 ReactJS, Arc Publishing/Fusion, Github, Bitbucket, SASS/SCSS, Jest, Jira/Confluence, Kanban

HUGE

SEP2018 - MAY2019

Senior Web Engineer

- Build ReactJS components from Abstract design system
- Required to write semantic HTML
- Strong knowledge of JavaScript (ES5, ES6+)
- Build components using styled components
- Proficient use of e2e testing (Jest) and validation (CircleCI)
- Proficient use of the terminal (git, npm, yarn, zsh)
- Proficient use of Git/Github for version control
- Collaborative environment, passion for learning encouraged
- Attended Kubernetes and React Hooks training

CLIENTS:

Lowes: Kiosk Project

• Bulma.io, TypeScript, Twillio Web Sockets, Sketch design files, Lottie/SVG Animation, Agile/Scrum

CNN: React Migration

• ReactJS, Storybook, CircleCI, Github, Styled Components, Abstract, LernaJS, Jest, Jira/Confluence, Kanban

ABOUT ME

Hi, I am a UI Engineer & Designer. I have worked on a large-scale ReactJS web application, WordPress Migration, Angular/ Bootstrap applications, mobile app design. I have experience building web/mobile apps and a published app in Apple and Google Play stores. I also have a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science and a diverse technical background. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and JavaScript frameworks while continuing to learn new technologies.

I love hackathons and creative collaboration!

SKILLS

UI DEVELOPMENT UI DESIGN UI PROTOTYPING

TECH TOOLS

Essentials:

HTML, Javascript (ES5/ES6+), CSS, SQL Frameworks: ReactJS, AngularJS(1+) Packages: npm, yarn, homebrew Static Site Generators: GatsbyJS CSS: SASS/SCSS, styled-components

Other Tooling:

Typescript, Storybook, Grunt, Express, Firebase, GraphQL, REST/ APIs, OAuth, ¡Query, Bootstrap, CircleCI, MongoDB, Jest, Abstract, Sketch, PUG, HAML, Flexbox, CSS Grid, Babel, Invision, Google AMP, Webpack, Google Web Designer, Agile, JIRA, Confluence, LernaJS, Lottie/SVG Animation, NodeJS

CMS:

Headless, Wordpress, Sitecore

Version Control: Git/Github, Bitbucket ADOBE CREATIVE CLOUD

Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, XD

EDUCATION

Bachelor Computer Science Columbus State University

Web Developer Certification **Emory Continuing Education**

LISA COPELAND

UI ENGINEER & DESIGNER

PORTFOLIO: http://www.stopdaydreaming.com

EMAIL: hello@stopdaydreaming.com

PHONE: 678.235.4961

GITHUB: https://github.com/stopdaydreaming

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Contractor

MAR2013 - SFP2018

UI Developer & Designer

- Developed a product demo microsite from Invision to HTML/CSS/Javascript (Fireshell, Grunt, Sass, Bootstrap, JQuery)
- Designed and developed content-rich iOS and Android app for Boys and Girls Club of America
- Front-end Developer for responsive, full-scale onboarding application from paper forms to completely online system (Bootstrap, AngularJS, Java backend)
- Lead Developer on migration from Sitecore to large scale custom and responsive Wordpress microsites for healthcare continuing education
- Design and Develop (Photoshop/InDesign files) to HTML Email campaigns in MailChimp, Constant Contact, Hubspot and ExactTarget
- Design and Develop HTML web banners using Google Designer and Adobe Animation
- Design and Develop new user facing features, with a focus on consistency and usability
- Collaborate with Graphic Designers, Backend Developers and QA to ensure projects from conception to delivery

NorthHigland Consulting/SparksGrove: Frontend Developer

Newell Rubbermaid: Digital Designer Boys & Girls Club America: UI Developer

Gwinnett County Public Schools: Frontend Developer

Verizon Wireless: UI Developer Cox Media/Manheim: Web Designer

Emory University

JUN2007 - MAR2013

Application Developer

- Redesigned an existing site which improved web usability, navigation, out-dated content, layout, design
- Designed + Developed using Adobe CS Tools, HTML, CSS PHP, MySQL, JavaScript
- Designed wireframes and mockups for development
- Developed online forms for managing account information and training registration
- · Managed weekly user meetings
- Review Google Analytics for site to improve user experience